So far, we've learned two algorithms that will fit a line through a set of points.
目前为止 我们已经学习了两个算法 用于让一条直线拟合一些点
One is using any of the tricks namely the absolute and the square trick,
其中一种方法是使用技巧 包括绝对值技巧和平方技巧
and the other one is minimizing any of the error functions
另一种方法是最小化任何误差函数
namely the mean absolute error and the mean squared error.
即平均绝对误差和均方误差
The interesting thing is that these two are actually the exact same thing.
有趣的是 这两个其实是完全相同的
What I'm saying is that when we minimize the mean absolute error,
我想说的是 我们最小化平均绝对误差时
we're using a gradient descent step and that
使用了梯度下降法
gradient descent step is the exact same thing as the absolute trick.
梯度下降法与绝对值技巧完全相同
Likewise, when we minimize the squared error,
同样地 我们最小化平方误差时
the gradient descent step is the exact same thing as the square trick.
梯度下降法与平方技巧完全相同
So let's see why, let's start with the mean squared error.
我们来看一下原因 首先来看均方误差
Here's a point with coordinates (x,
这里点的坐标为 (x,y)
y) and here's our line with equation y-hat equals w_1 times x plus w_2.
这条直线方程为 y-hat = W1 x + W2
So y-hat is our prediction and the line predicts the y coordinate of this point
所以 y-hat 是预测 这条直线可以预测这个点的纵坐标
that prediction gives us a point on the line that
这个预测可以给我们直线上的某个点
matches the x coordinate of the point (x,y).
使这个点的横坐标与点 (x,y) 相拟合
So it's the point (x,y-hat).
因此这个点的坐标为 (x, y-hat)
Now, the error for this point is 1.5 times y minus y-hat squared,
现在这个点的误差是 (y-y-hat)² 的二分之一
and the mean squared error for this set of points is the average of all these errors.
并且这些点的均方误差是这些误差的平均数
But since average is a linear function,
不过既然平均数是线性函数
then whatever we do here applies to the entire error.
那么我们这里无论怎么做 都可以适用于整个误差
Now, we know that the gradient descent step uses these two derivatives,
现在我们知道梯度下降法使用这两个导数
namely the derivative with respect to the slope
分别是关于斜率 W1 的导数
w_1 and the derivative with respect to the y-intercept w_2.
和关于 y 轴截距 W2 的导数
If we calculate the derivatives,
如果我们计算这些导数
and you can see the calculation in detail in the instructor notes,
你可以在教学笔记里看到详细的运算
we get negative times y minus y-hat times x for the one respect to the slope
我们得到关于斜率的导数是 - (y-y-hat)x
and negative times y minus y-hat for the one with respect to the y-intercept w_2.
关于 y 轴截距 w2 的导数是 - (y-y-hat)
And notice that the length of this red segment is precisely (y minus
我注意到这个红色线段的长度是 (y-y-hat)
y-hat) and the length of this green segment is precisely x.
这个绿色线段的长度是 x
And if you remember correctly,
并且如果还记得的话
the square trick told us that we have to upgrade the slope by
平方技巧告诉我们 我们通过加上 (y-y-hat)x
adding y minus y-hat times x times the learning rate alpha,
再乘以学习率 α 来提高斜率
and upgrade the y-intercept by adding y minus y-hat times the learning rate alpha.
通过加上 (y-y-hat) 乘以学习率 α 来提高 y 轴截距
But that is precisely what this gradient descent step is doing.
不过这是梯度下降法所做的
If you like, feel free to pause the video or actually write it down
如果你愿意 可以暂停这个视频 或者
in a little piece of paper to verify that is the exact same calculation.
在一张纸上写下来 验证是否是完全相同的运算
So this is why the gradient descent step utilize when we
这就是为什么最小化均方误差时使用梯度下降法
minimize the mean squared error is the same as the square trick.
与平方技巧相同的原因
We can do the same thing with the absolute trick.
我们对绝对值技巧可以采取相同做法
The procedure is very similar except we have to be careful about the sign.
步骤也非常相似 除了要注意符号
This is our error, the absolute value of
这是我们的误差 绝对值 |y - y-hat|
y minus y-hat and the derivatives of the error with respect
关于 W1 误差导数为 ±x
to w_1 and w_2 are plus or minus x and
W2误差导数为 ±1
plus or minus one based on the point is on top or underneath the line.
正负号取决于这个点位于直线的上方还是下方
Since the distance is x,
由于距离为 x
then you can also check that this is precisely what
你也可以检查这是否是
the gradient descent step does when we minimize the mean absolute error.
我们最小化平均绝对误差时使用的梯度下降法
So that's it, that's why minimizing these errors with gradient descent is
所以就是这样 这就是我使用梯度下降法最小化这些误差的原因
the exact same thing that using the absolute and the square tricks.
与使用绝对值技巧和平方技巧完全相同